A Guide to the Loudoun Laurels Collection, 2008-2012
Thomas Balch Library
Thomas Balch Library
Loudoun Laurels Collection 2008-2013
Thomas Balch Library
M 045
This collection consists of the oral histories produced by the Loudoun Laurels Foundation, programs from the awards galas, material from the 2009 Founders' Committee meeting, and photocopies of publicity articles from The Middleburg Eccentric. The oral histories are recorded on DVDs and range in length from just over one hour to almost four hours. Use copies of each DVD are available in the collection and may be viewed on a portable DVD player donated by Daniel Morrow to be used with the Loudoun Laurels Collection.
Loudoun Laurels Foundation, Waterford, VA.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection open for research.
Acquisition Information
Loudoun Laurels Foundation, Waterford, VA.
Alternative Form Available
Electronic media
Accruals
2009.0047, 2009.0047, 2009.0141, 2009.0207, 2009.0213, 2011.0273; 2012.0166; 2014.0023
Historical Information
In 1912, Leesburg Hospital was established on Market Street in Leesburg, Virginia. The hospital went through several name changes over the years, and in 2005 completed a merger with Inova Health System to become Inova Loudoun Hospital. The hospital's fundraising organization, the Loudoun Healthcare Foundation, created the Loudoun Laurels in 2008 as a way to honor individuals and organizations for service to Loudoun County, and to foster a sense of community. The nominating body for the Loudoun Laurels is the Founders' Committee, also formed in 2008. It is composed of community leaders and past Laureates.
There are seven categories in which an individual or organization may be nominated: business and not-for-profit, education, lifetime service, philanthropy, science and technology, statesmanship, and stewardship. The stated goals of the program are to introduce community leaders to each other and to the public; to engage and inspire Loudoun County; recognize service to Loudoun County; and to encourage a sense of community. The Founders' Committee may honor up to three people each year and the Laureates are honored at a gala each fall that also serves as an annual fundraiser.
In addition to honoring individuals, the Loudoun Laurels also serves as an oral history project. Each honoree participates in recording an audio-visual oral history to document his or her life, history, and contributions to Loudoun County. The oral histories are currently conducted by Daniel Morrow, publisher of a local newspaper, The Middleburg Eccentric.
In 2010, the Loudoun Laurels became an independent, not-for-profit foundation. The CEO of Inova Loudoun Hospital continues to serve on the Founders' Committee, but the program is no longer part of the Loudoun Healthcare Foundation.
Scope and Content
This collection consists of the oral histories produced by the Loudoun Laurels Foundation, programs from the awards galas, material from the 2009 Founders' Committee meeting, and photocopies of publicity articles from The Middleburg Eccentric. The oral histories are recorded on DVDs and range in length from just over one hour to almost four hours. Use copies of each DVD are available in the collection and may be viewed on a portable DVD player donated by Daniel Morrow to be used with the Loudoun Laurels Collection.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Bibliography
Jacks, Jason. "Childs Burden: Preserving the past." Loudoun Times-Mirror, September 3, 2008.
"Inova Loudoun Hospital to Honor Two Dedicated Community Leaders." Inova Newsroom. September 3, 2009. http://newsroom.inova.org/article_print.cfm?article_id=5312
The Ladies Board of Inova Loudoun Hospital, 1912- (M 049), Thomas Balch Library, Leesburg, VA.
Loudoun Laurels Collection, 2008-2011 (M 045), Thomas Balch Library, Leesburg, VA.
Other Finding Aid
None
Technical Requirements
Electronic media
Related Material
The Ladies Board of Inova Hospital, 1912- (M 049), Thomas Balch Library, Leesburg, VA.
Contents List
- (Box 1)
  - Program (2 copies), 2008
  - Program (3 copies), 2009
  - Program (2 copies), 2010
  - Program (2 copies), 2011
  - Program (2 copies), 2012
  - Founders' Committee Meeting, 2009
  - Photographs, 2012
  - Publicity, 2010-2012
- (Box 2)
  - Oral Histories:
    Childs Frick Burden, 2008
    G. Kimball Hart, 2008
    Eugene Scheel (in two parts), 2008
    Karen Russell, 2009
    Paul Ziluca (in two parts), 2009
    Joe T. May, 2010
    Judy and Lang Washburn, 2010
    James P. Roberts, 2011
    Robert E. Sevila, 2011
    Stanley Caulkins, 2012
    Fred Drummond, 2012
    Edgar Hatrick, 2013
    Juan Jose Nagera and Sara Litke, 2013
    Su Webb, 2013